

# Saoirse Mullan Digital Designer



www.saoirsemullan.com



hello@saoirsemullan.com



07565895806



Belfast, N.I



saoirsemullan



@saoirsemullan



@saoirsemullan

# About Me

A designer with a keen interest in User Experience, User Interface & Graphic Design.

I'm a confident, highly motivated and creative student determined to succeed in the tech and design industry, continuously learning new techniques, software and keeping up with emerging trends. Actively attending UX, Women in Tech and Digital design meet-ups in Belfast. I am Graphic & Digital Designer at Ulster University while in my final year of studies, with over 19 months of industry experience.

# Experience

# Graphic & Digital Designer

Ulster University | Belfast | September 2019 - Present

- Edit and design the Ulster University website using Squiz CMS and ensure all online content meets accessibility guidelines
- Edit and maintain the Ulster University website to ensure it meets user experience expectations of students and staff
- Create marketing material such as email banners, social media graphics and brochures and leaflets which are promoted across all university campuses

#### **Design Intern**

Snack At Franks | Belfast | July 2019 - September 2019

- · Worked within a start-up company to help generate creative concepts for promotional purposes
- Produced materials such as flyers and cards for the subscription box
- Developed graphic design and illustrative work using Adobe Illustrator, InDesign and Procreate

#### Web Design Intern

Ulster University | Jordanstown | September 2018 – July 2019

- Updated, redesigned and redeveloped Universities Employability Portal covering both student and staff view
- Improved a key system covering user's digital experience for employability by updating layouts, graphics and content
- Optimised front-end efficiency and deployed content management using Squiz and October CMS
- Designed graphics for web and print promoting career services
- Designed posters, email graphics, leaflets, flyers and PowerPoint presentations
- Illustrated designs for instituted wide employability initiative (UU Create-A Enterprise program: including a lanyard, pen, notepad and certificates)
- Refined my understanding of HTML, CSS and JavaScript
- Value of time management to tight deadlines and prioritising workload
- Increased web usability, accessibility and standards

# **Skills**

#### UX/UI

- Problem Solving
- Interaction Design
- Empathy Mapping
- Information Architecture
- User experience
- Wireframing
- Prototyping
- User-centred Design
- User Personas
- User Journeys
- User Testing
- Problem Solving
- UX Competitor Analysis

#### Front-end Skills

- HTML5
- CSS3
- JavaScript
- GitHub

#### Software & Technology

- Adobe Creative Suite
- Microsoft Office
- Adobe XD
- Figma
- InVision

#### Graphic Design

- Typography
- Brand Identity
- Icon Design
- Illustration

# Other Work Experience

#### Waitress

- Salt Bistro: May 2018 August 2018
- Malmaison: December 2016 November 2017
- Titanic Belfast: April 2016 November 2016

## **Education & Qualifications**

# BDes Hons Interaction Design | Ulster University | 2019-2020 Interaction Design at the Belfast School of Art.

- Major Project Prototyping
- Research & Writing
- Design Presentation & Reporting

# BSc Hons Interactive Multimedia Design | Ulster University | 2016-2020

Completed a three-year undergraduate degree on a high 2:1. Some modules included:

- Dynamic Web Authoring Client View & Server View
- Introduction to Communication Design
- Managing Web Platforms and Content
- Creative Entrepreneurship

## Level 3 Diploma ICT | Belfast Metropolitan College | 2015-2016 Attained a double grade Distinction\* Distinction

#### MA Hons English | University of Dundee | 2014-2015

Studied English, Film Studies and Philosophy. Obtained a certificate of Higher Education after receiving a First.

# A Levels | Limavady Grammar School |2012-2014

Art & Design: B

English Literature and Language: B

Politics: D

## GCSE'S | St Mary's Limavady | 2007-2012

10 GCSE'S: C in Maths, B in Additional Maths and a B in English.

#### References

Brian Byers Employability Manager B.byers@ulster.ac.uk 07515570706

Paul McCormack Course Director, Interaction Design, Ulster University p.mccormack@ulster.ac.uk

# Additional Achievements & Accreditations

- Ulster EDGE Excel Award November 2019
- Womenfolk Mentoring program: May October 2019
- Kainos A.I. Camp: August 2019
- CitiSpire 6 Month Mentoring Program: December 2018 May 2019
- Digital Skills Training Program BuzzStart Academy in partnership with Facebook: May 2019
- UU Create Enterprise Program: April 2019
- UUSU Leadership Program Level 4 OCN in Leadership: March 2019
- UOTC Leadership in Practice: January 2019
- Belfast City Marathon Raised over £1,000 for Foyle Hospice & finished 9-mile walk: May 2019
- Essential First Aid Training John Ambulance: March 2019 March 2021
- Code First: Girls 8-week Web Development Course & Ambassador: October – December 2018
- Millennium Volunteer Award: September December 2014